<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>People &#8211; Cluefill</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cluefill.com/category/people/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cluefill.com</link>
	<description>World of Randomness...</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 18:18:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cluefill.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Cluefill-Favicon.png</url>
	<title>People &#8211; Cluefill</title>
	<link>https://cluefill.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Top 10 Greatest Facts about Nikola Tesla &#038; his untold Story&#8230;</title>
		<link>https://cluefill.com/top-10-greatest-facts-about-nikola-tesla-his-untold-story/</link>
					<comments>https://cluefill.com/top-10-greatest-facts-about-nikola-tesla-his-untold-story/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dinesh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 17:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here are some interesting facts about Nikola Tesla that many people may not know. Nikola Tesla’s Ideas weren’t recognized by ... <a title="Top 10 Greatest Facts about Nikola Tesla &#038; his untold Story&#8230;" class="read-more" href="https://cluefill.com/top-10-greatest-facts-about-nikola-tesla-his-untold-story/" aria-label="More on Top 10 Greatest Facts about Nikola Tesla &#038; his untold Story&#8230;">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>Here are some interesting facts about Nikola Tesla that many people may not know.</h2>



<ul>
<li>Nikola Tesla was a polyglot and spoke eight languages fluently, including English, German, French, Italian, Hungarian, Czech, Serbo-Croatian, and Latin.</li>



<li>He was a vegetarian and had a fear of germs, which caused him to avoid eating meat.</li>



<li>Tesla was an early advocate of wireless communication, and his experiments led to the development of radio.</li>



<li>He was a cat lover and had several cats throughout his life.</li>



<li>He was a strong believer in the power of the mind and often gave lectures on the power of positive thinking.</li>



<li>He was a prolific inventor, with over 300 patents to his name.</li>



<li>He was a fan of pigeons and often fed them in the park near his apartment.</li>



<li>He was a fan of literature, particularly Shakespeare, and was often seen reading at his laboratory.</li>



<li>He was a strong believer in the power of the imagination and often said, “The vision that you glorify in your mind, the ideal that you enthrone in your heart – this you will build your life by, and this you will become.”</li>



<li>He was a fan of music and was known to play the violin. He also invented the Tesla Coil, which is used to create musical notes.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjiP8PxB7OfHtXAKu7HtQhBjullGHtyiusbNUldT-SiBU6EFCuHjMV3JcyhIYaCCjH-37A-xt6LQMUbajbM68a1xHY4rSVn_YzQLbI80jE11cML8RZWd0RxuG7JLfkjuorwUHOlAmuaAULeOAEsL-hq2AdH_SroGJb20v5WygzJuXaspPmsdIgRQuAlYA/s990/image-5.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjiP8PxB7OfHtXAKu7HtQhBjullGHtyiusbNUldT-SiBU6EFCuHjMV3JcyhIYaCCjH-37A-xt6LQMUbajbM68a1xHY4rSVn_YzQLbI80jE11cML8RZWd0RxuG7JLfkjuorwUHOlAmuaAULeOAEsL-hq2AdH_SroGJb20v5WygzJuXaspPmsdIgRQuAlYA/w320-h143/image-5.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Nikola Tesla’s Ideas weren’t recognized by everyone</h2>



<p>Despite his many accomplishments, Nikola Tesla was not considered as a better scientist by many people due to his unorthodox methods and eccentric personality. He was considered to be a visionary and was ahead of his time in many regards, but his unconventional approach to science and technology did not sit well with many people. Additionally, his ambitious ideas and projects often failed to materialize due to lack of funding and resources. These factors contributed to his lack of recognition in his lifetime, despite his many accomplishments.</p>



<h2>Futuristic Ideas of Nikola Tesla</h2>



<p>Nikola Tesla had a wide range of ideas and theories outside of his inventions. Many of his theories focused on the power of energy, frequency and vibration, and he believed that all matter was composed of these elements. He also developed the concept of scalar waves, which he believed could be used to transmit energy, information and even time travel.</p>



<p>He was also a proponent of free energy and believed that a form of energy could be harnessed from the Earth’s atmosphere. He developed theories on the use of wireless power transmission, as well as robotics and artificial intelligence. Additionally, he had ideas on the use of electricity as a form of medicine and healing, as well as the concept of a “world brain” that could be used to share knowledge and ideas.</p>



<h2>Time Travel Idea of Nikola Tesla</h2>



<p>Nikola Tesla did not focus more on time travel for a few reasons. Firstly, he was far ahead of his time and his theories were often considered too outlandish to be taken seriously. Additionally, time travel was not a topic that was widely discussed or accepted in the late 19th and early 20th centuries, and Tesla likely felt that more research and experimentation was needed before it could be taken seriously. Finally, Tesla was a prolific inventor, and he likely felt that his time was better spent on more practical inventions, such as wireless power transmission and robotics.</p>



<p>Nikola Tesla’s wireless power transmission is possible in real life. Wireless power transmission is a technology that uses electromagnetic fields to transfer energy from a source to a receiver without the need for any physical connection. This technology has been used in a variety of applications, including powering medical implants, charging electric vehicles, and providing lighting. Tesla’s own experiments with wireless power transmission have been replicated, and wireless power transmission is now a reality.</p>



<p>Nikola Tesla was a highly respected scientist and inventor, and his work was admired by many. However, his ideas and theories were often controversial and not always accepted by the scientific community. Tesla had a number of well-known supporters, including Thomas <a class="wpil_keyword_link" href="https://cluefill.com/2023/02/22/thomas-alva-edisons-astonishing-story/" title="Edison" data-wpil-keyword-link="linked">Edison</a> and Mark Twain, but also encountered criticism and resistance from some quarters.</p>



<p>Some of his incomplete inventions or ideas include long-range wireless energy transfer, electric powered supersonic airships, humanoid robots, and controlling flows or fluid current. Tesla’s work in these areas was ahead of its time and has only recently been appreciated by scientists. For example, his invention to control flows or fluid currents is now being used in ways that were not previously realized.</p>



<p>Elon Musk is a fan of Nikola Tesla. He has said that Tesla is an inspiration to him, and has donated a million dollars to the Tesla Science Centre in honor of the inventor. He has also named his electric car company Tesla Motors in tribute to Tesla’s work.</p>



<h2>Nikola Tesla’s End</h2>



<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nikola_Tesla" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nikola Tesla</a>&nbsp;died on Jan 7, 1943, alone and in debt, on the 33rd floor of the Hotel New Yorker. He was 86 and had been in declining health for the last 10 years of his life. He was found in his bed by a maid, having passed away from a coronary thrombosis.</p>



<h2>How are Nikola Tesla’s greatest inventions used by everyone today?</h2>



<p>When you use any device that is powered by electricity, you have a&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nikola_Tesla" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Nikola Tesla</a>&nbsp;is one of the greatest scientists to ever live. However, even though the genius had a weird personal life, he left some pretty terrifying predictions that the authorities tried to keep secret but have just been made public.</p>



<p>Most times the lives of brilliant figures are interesting, but Nikola Tesla’s life was much more than interesting even as he left behind a legacy that will last forever. Nikola Tesla was born in 1856 as an Austro-Hungarian Empire subject in the mountainous region of Lika on the Balkan Peninsula.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjDPqsNj98u25vsh25U8IdtkWVabprUsfEe4740xjuYmj6qTlcAc2Y7Fpy0gU2u9fRHBNfHLjELs6nokY5xoqVCLl3vLNDnph0CFXTGv2FF3U_Xo5zZeH5mUiDRIpkBt2pzOFodQM9UcknapNEeR3FV_hVpw3SyUQpdZc3ufHGi3qHAnV9QmUsaNFMF-g/s1036/image-2.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjDPqsNj98u25vsh25U8IdtkWVabprUsfEe4740xjuYmj6qTlcAc2Y7Fpy0gU2u9fRHBNfHLjELs6nokY5xoqVCLl3vLNDnph0CFXTGv2FF3U_Xo5zZeH5mUiDRIpkBt2pzOFodQM9UcknapNEeR3FV_hVpw3SyUQpdZc3ufHGi3qHAnV9QmUsaNFMF-g/w320-h179/image-2.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>His father, Malutin, and mother, Duca, were both of Serbian descent. Tesla’s father was a stern but loving Orthodox priest who also happened to be a gifted writer and poet. Tesla immersed himself in his father’s library from a young age, and Tesla obviously got some of his creative traits from his mother, who was a hard-working woman with many talents. She designed appliances to help with household and farm chores, including a mechanical egg beater.</p>



<p>Tesla began his education at home and later attended a gymnasium in Carlstadt, Croatia, where he excelled in his studies. During this time, young Nico came across a steel engraving of Niagara Falls in his mind. A massive water wheel was being turned by the more powerful current. He solemnly told an uncle that one day he would travel to America and capture energy in this manner, and he did exactly that 30 years later.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiPmpE_6wlnSAk5UXrKMS5VYotz1re4yzI51PAtx8IZxSEHS3ED5ItUU_fOCsF63Qk9Lt71jBuB3ZJJSse74szXS7pz4tH99U2DFfB393PJj7GYo0xzBMdd_ayrXbJiypzQCYxHdgEI-JIXI8G_yxkl1sWYnxvocRfLhPEeNToE-wXaejgWVYED8Zu4BA/s1534/image-1.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiPmpE_6wlnSAk5UXrKMS5VYotz1re4yzI51PAtx8IZxSEHS3ED5ItUU_fOCsF63Qk9Lt71jBuB3ZJJSse74szXS7pz4tH99U2DFfB393PJj7GYo0xzBMdd_ayrXbJiypzQCYxHdgEI-JIXI8G_yxkl1sWYnxvocRfLhPEeNToE-wXaejgWVYED8Zu4BA/s320/image-1.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>Tesla began his mechanical and electrical engineering studies at the Polytechnic School, where it didn’t take long for his brilliance to shine through. One day, a physics teacher showed Tesla’s class a new Graham Dynamo, which could be used as both a motor and a generator by using direct current. After observing it for a while, Tesla speculated that it might be possible to eliminate commutators, which are inefficient sparking connections.</p>



<p>His professor joked that this would be like constructing a perpetual motion machine, but Tesla would not let go of the idea, which he pondered for years, and he intuitively knew that the solution lay in alternating electric currents. It wasn’t until Tesla was 24 and working for the central telephone exchange in Budapest that the answer came to him.</p>



<p>He said one afternoon he was walking through the city park with a friend and reciting poetry when a portion of the poem he uttered jolted an idea in his might. He quickly grabbed a stick and drew the diagram on the set, and the wild has not been the same since.</p>



<h2>Company that hired Tesla</h2>



<p>Tesla was hired by electric power companies in Strasbourg and Paris to improve their DC generation facilities after his discovery in Budapest. He tried unsuccessfully to interest investors in his AC motor concept in Germany and France, but it was obvious that in order to realize his vision he would need to meet another of the world’s greatest electrical engineers.</p>



<p>Thomas Alva Edison Tesla arrived in New York City at the age of 28 and was astounded by what he found; he stated that he left behind a very beautiful artistic and fascinating homeland to live in a place that was machined rough and unappealing the genius felt America was a century behind Europe in terms of civilization.</p>



<p>While Tesla, the Serbian immigrant, hoped to start a new life with four cents in his pockets, some mathematical computations, a drawing of the Flying Machine concept, Tesla’s life would intertwine with Edison’s in the late 1870s, when electricity was first introduced to New York.</p>



<h2>Edison and Tesla</h2>



<p>Edison’s incandescent lamp sparked unprecedented demand for electricity, and his direct current power plant on Pearl Street in lower Manhattan quickly became a monopoly. Single poles carried dozens of crooked crossbeams supporting sagging wires on the streets, and exposed electrical wiring was a constant danger. Unwary children would scale the poles only to meet an untimely electrical death. I know two grey men, and you are one of them; this young man is the other. Tesla then went on to describe his engineering work and plans for an alternating current motor, despite Edison’s lack of knowledge and desire to learn more.</p>



<p>Edison perceived AC power as a threat, but there was something different about Tesla, and Edison hired him right away to improve his DC generation plans. Tesla claimed Edison promised him fifty thousand dollars if he succeeded, possibly thinking it was an impossible task, but the prospect of so much money was great motivation for the poor immigrant. Tesla and Edison shared a genius trait in that neither of them seemed to require much sleep. Edison could go on for days catnapping on a sofa in his office.</p>



<p>Tesla claimed that he worked from 10 p.m. to 5 a.m. the next day to build the Edison Machine. Tesla claimed that even in his old age he only slept two or three hours per night. The resemblance ended there, though Tesla relied on flashes of inspiration, visualizing the invention in his mind before proceeding to the construction stage. Edison was a trial and error man who defined invention as “five percent inspiration and 95 percent perspiration.” Edison was a self-taught artist.</p>



<p>After Tesla received his formal education in Europe, it was only a matter of time before the differences became a source of contention. Tesla announced the completion of his work several months after Edison hired him.</p>



<p>When Tesla asked to be paid, Edison was taken aback. He explained that the fifty thousand dollar offer was made in jest. Tesla resigned immediately, shocked and disgusted to be fired, and went bankrupt. Tesla turned to menial jobs. The word soon spread that a foreigner with unusual talent was digging ditches to survive. Investors approached Tesla and requested that he develop a better method for arc lighting.</p>



<h2>Financial agreement</h2>



<p>Despite the fact that this was not the opportunity he had hoped for, the group agreed to finance the Tesla electric light company. Tesla got to work and created a one-of-a-kind r-clamp with a beautiful design and efficiency. Unfortunately, Tesla was out of his depth in the financial aspects; all of the profits went to the investors, leaving Tesla with a pile of worthless stock certificates, but his fortunes were about to change. Mr. A.K. Brown of Western Union agreed to invest in Tesla’s AC motor concept.</p>



<p>Tesla quickly developed all of the components of the system of alternating current power generation and transmission that is used universally throughout the world today in a small laboratory just a short distance from Edison’s office during this time, saying, “The motors I built there were exactly as I imagined them. I made no attempt to improve the design instead simply reproducing the images as they appeared to my eyes.”</p>



<p>Tesla applied for seven U.S. patents in the field of polyphase AC motors and power transmission in November and December of 1887 for a complete system of generators, transformers, and transmission lines. Motors and lighting were included.</p>



<h2>How could a man look into the future needs?</h2>



<p>Here are some of the genius’s predictions. Number one, when Wireless is perfectly applied, the entire earth will be converted into a huge brain, in which all things, being particles of a real and rhythmic hope, will be able to communicate with one another instantly regardless of distance; not only that, but through television and telephony.</p>



<p>We will see and hear one another as perfectly as if we were face to face despite intervening distances of thousands of miles; and the instruments through which we shall see and hear one another as perfectly as All forms of static interference will be eliminated so that innumerable transmitters and receivers may be operated without interference.</p>



<p>It is more than probable that the household’s daily newspaper will be printed wirelessly in the home during the night, and domestic management problems of heat, light, and household mechanics will be freed from all labour through beneficent wireless power.</p>



<p>This is the Wi-Fi you connect to every day, starting as early as 1898. I propose to representatives of a large manufacturing concern the construction and public exhibition of an automobile. Carriage, if left to its own devices, would perform a wide range of operations involving something resembling judgment. This is the self-driving car; interestingly, a company named after him is one of the leaders in autonomous driving with autopilot number four.</p>



<p>When wireless power transmission becomes commercial, transport and transmission will be revolutionized. Already, motion pictures have been transmitted wirelessly over a short distance; later, the distance will be limitable, and by later, I mean only a few years hence. Perhaps the most valuable application of wireless energy will be the propulsion of flying machines that will carry no fuel and be free from any limitations of the present airplanes.</p>



<h3>The Wireless Ideas</h3>



<p>We shall ride from New York to Europe in a few hours. International boundaries will be largely obliterated, and a great step will be made towards the unification and harmonious existence of the various races inhabiting The Globe Wireless will not only make possible the supply of energy to regions that are otherwise inaccessible, but it will also be effective politically by harmonizing international interests and creating understanding instead of differences. These would be planes that do not need refueling.</p>



<p>The concept is based on the ability to transmit energy over long distances without using wires. number six I expect to photograph thoughts in 1893, while engaged in certain investigations, I became convinced that a definite image formed in thought must, by reflex action, produce a corresponding image on the retina which could be read by a suitable apparatus.</p>



<p>Now, if it is true that a thought reflects an image on the retina, it is a simple matter of illuminating the same property and taking photographs, and then using the ordinary methods which are available to project the image on a suitable apparatus.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhyCYq84NCdkOp4ioi7aH9MRraRWflcNVRnxwjOg7WZqCKVYTWb4ugq2wKBA0Hc-9ZKBnrLqr6naA99HDYT2S8_-HFCjPWWLUp3DoNcykmqvleyxq7a7YRaoofZfTnA00rWjLkjk-AMSiS0akWh0n8ty3jvNP5QivSaEyyLxGt97DxLyuIJu5HJihEU8Q/s799/image-3.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhyCYq84NCdkOp4ioi7aH9MRraRWflcNVRnxwjOg7WZqCKVYTWb4ugq2wKBA0Hc-9ZKBnrLqr6naA99HDYT2S8_-HFCjPWWLUp3DoNcykmqvleyxq7a7YRaoofZfTnA00rWjLkjk-AMSiS0akWh0n8ty3jvNP5QivSaEyyLxGt97DxLyuIJu5HJihEU8Q/s320/image-3.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>I believe that the development of the Flying Machine will outpace that of the automobile, and I anticipate that Mr. Ford will make significant contributions to this progress. The problem of parking automobiles and providing separate roads for commercial and pleasure traffic will be solved, belted parking towers will spring up in our major cities, and roads will be multiplied out of sheer necessity until they are rendered obsolete when civilization exchanges wheels for winks.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiQgujdLX0q7xfZMQdX6RItS7sHZ7yWXfQwRdPCm8kWBCK_hQePb48m8qmVWrQ0cKFhmR1F6IfiFMIQ4BvXR1gA-T-sXFEh-uLPmH9Zh3VOlF4XQ_qjJPTTj0LRvafe3Bnmd4RPMJO4jd47wsIS67Qs_NO1ev_Wi2bCGJG9KeGcuONqJgsw40bY1WAqgQ/s757/image-4.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiQgujdLX0q7xfZMQdX6RItS7sHZ7yWXfQwRdPCm8kWBCK_hQePb48m8qmVWrQ0cKFhmR1F6IfiFMIQ4BvXR1gA-T-sXFEh-uLPmH9Zh3VOlF4XQ_qjJPTTj0LRvafe3Bnmd4RPMJO4jd47wsIS67Qs_NO1ev_Wi2bCGJG9KeGcuONqJgsw40bY1WAqgQ/s320/image-4.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>The FBI finally declassified some 250 pages of Tesla-related documents under the Freedom of Information Act in 2016 after years of Fielding questions about possible cover-ups, the bureau followed up with two more releases, the most recent in March 2018. Despite the release of these documents, many questions remain unanswered, and some of Tesla’s files remain unaccounted for three weeks after his death.</p>



<p>According to the declassified documents, an electrical engineer from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) was tasked with reviewing his papers to see if they contained any ideas of significant value. Dr. John G. Trump stated that his analysis revealed Tesla’s efforts to be primarily speculative, philosophical, and promotional in nature, and that the papers did not include new, sound, workable principles or methods for realizing such results. The scientist’s name is undoubtedly familiar because John G. Trump was the uncle of Donald J. Trump, the 45th President of the United States.</p>



<p>He was the younger brother of Trump’s father Fred and helped design x-ray machines that helped cancer patients as well as work on radar research for the allies during World War II. Then there’s the perplexing issue of the missing files. Tesla’s files and other materials were sent to Belgrade, Serbia, in 1952 after a U.S. court declared Kuzmanovic the rightful heir to his uncle’s estate, where they now reside in the Nicola Tesla Museum.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>To conclude, Nikola Tesla was a genius inventor and scientist who made incredible contributions to science and technology. His inventions and theories laid the foundation for many modern technologies, and his ideas continue to inspire innovation today. His work in the field of electricity revolutionized the world and he is widely respected for his ground breaking ideas and inventions. Tesla’s ideas and inventions are considered ahead of their time, and many believe that technology is still missing his genius.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cluefill.com/top-10-greatest-facts-about-nikola-tesla-his-untold-story/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thomas Alva Edison’s astonishing story of bulb : 15 year old boy’s Idea</title>
		<link>https://cluefill.com/thomas-alva-edisons-astonishing-story/</link>
					<comments>https://cluefill.com/thomas-alva-edisons-astonishing-story/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dinesh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 11:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edison]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thomas Alva Edison one of the greatest inventors ever. He was photographed next to a lightbulb so often that people ... <a title="Thomas Alva Edison’s astonishing story of bulb : 15 year old boy’s Idea" class="read-more" href="https://cluefill.com/thomas-alva-edisons-astonishing-story/" aria-label="More on Thomas Alva Edison’s astonishing story of bulb : 15 year old boy’s Idea">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Thomas Alva Edison one of the greatest inventors ever. He was photographed next to a lightbulb so often that people came to believe he invented it. But he didn’t. Several inventors had demonstrated various versions of incandescent lights before he patented the first commercially successful lightbulb. He never crafted something out of nothing. His genius lay in his ability to craft something better. To perfect what was already available. His critics say his only real invention was taking credit for the inventions of others.</p>



<h2>Was he America’s greatest inventor, or…was Edison a thief?</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiXJAIyIfpMqaN2a02f7_DZ3xkGWu8nNKObI9ad3t1gmXAyKQO740fP-5xPOeUlvcjqjeigmfJpEX1fz1KL7GeAs8qYGxPUqhV-kxVn8Xncs6gTRQ7SFkKC4N9drY0BvO-K8hI6HSRxbw2dFTs-cY313VRaI43C-6zXq97jKftO8IbBoe3X0L9JckzVFw/s412/image-10.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiXJAIyIfpMqaN2a02f7_DZ3xkGWu8nNKObI9ad3t1gmXAyKQO740fP-5xPOeUlvcjqjeigmfJpEX1fz1KL7GeAs8qYGxPUqhV-kxVn8Xncs6gTRQ7SFkKC4N9drY0BvO-K8hI6HSRxbw2dFTs-cY313VRaI43C-6zXq97jKftO8IbBoe3X0L9JckzVFw/w320-h317/image-10.png" alt="Edison Discussing" title="Edison's Discussion"/></a></figure>



<p>His life changed when he was 15 years old. One day, when he saw a station official’s young son playing by the tracks in the path of an oncoming train, he rescued two-year-old Jimmie Mackenzie before a train crushed him. The boy’s father was deeply grateful and taught Edison how to operate Morse code on a telegraph machine. This was not easy to do; operators had to quickly send out signals in dots and dashes, which were converted into letters that made up words and phrases.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEioXkWNbJoMkfOkITEQTm3FxbbqKfZStFem3KCxk2dnnuTCR7cfhdG79Q_bmWxhSKqX8_gsr_Rv-vwHK_IN2ASLzs4v8WSpb7fRJMMLi-g19cj8ZcuiYWBPRTeLf16MdXbAA9diZ0BIkjnbhw1hKJnadRtM8WiP9xzmQnYo12EGOaD4FYopWkJIwYOqKA/s568/image-11.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEioXkWNbJoMkfOkITEQTm3FxbbqKfZStFem3KCxk2dnnuTCR7cfhdG79Q_bmWxhSKqX8_gsr_Rv-vwHK_IN2ASLzs4v8WSpb7fRJMMLi-g19cj8ZcuiYWBPRTeLf16MdXbAA9diZ0BIkjnbhw1hKJnadRtM8WiP9xzmQnYo12EGOaD4FYopWkJIwYOqKA/w205-h320/image-11.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>He began working full-time as a telegraph operator in Michigan, where he grew up, and later traveled around America, working at different offices for years. He was able to do this even though he was moderately deaf. He then decided to devote himself to a life as an inventor. Well, he mainly improved upon what was already invented. In 1874, he developed an advanced version of a telegraph machine that could send and receive four telegraph messages simultaneously on a single wire – two in each direction.</p>



<p>His quadruplex telegraph machine enabled his former employer Western Union to save money because the company could now send more messages without having to build new lines. Western Union purchased the rights to the invention for $10,000, around $260,000 in value today. Edison used the money to build his great laboratory at Menlo Park, New Jersey. He began by perfecting the telephone there.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgXdaiUgmcmTVBzFL_lTjy4auYz6lGMNArPmrr3qjZQ7QfGMisH64nL0wjm4DIQoN_AKJj4iM1UB60AcsKEUYyha8sYrltj4-yVDA7xfcIxTDh0XT4MXvEK3FN290WAz8sVP_G3d_Z1ANBqwXRVdk7K2hLMJAs_JC6dyR6U9V9CYULvW2-MWybFw3Q4BQ/s730/image-12.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgXdaiUgmcmTVBzFL_lTjy4auYz6lGMNArPmrr3qjZQ7QfGMisH64nL0wjm4DIQoN_AKJj4iM1UB60AcsKEUYyha8sYrltj4-yVDA7xfcIxTDh0XT4MXvEK3FN290WAz8sVP_G3d_Z1ANBqwXRVdk7K2hLMJAs_JC6dyR6U9V9CYULvW2-MWybFw3Q4BQ/w320-h206/image-12.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>By 1876, Alexander Graham Bell had found a way to transmit human voices over wires. The telephone was revolutionary. Western Union commissioned him to improve upon Bell’s invention, to make it practical, and so Edison worked on a telephone transmitter. While working to perfect the phone, he also tried to record the human voice. The phonograph put Edison on the map – giving him the nickname the “Wizard of Menlo Park”. He began to expand his factory…and his appetite for other inventions.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiBoC9uWYHa80_quSEnAf6KSWUAeFNmUhJ-qfSQ1evZ1kHlYi-EcSxOnUb73ZM8b0zHZNXDMhKnoLfq1oGNF7tim0Sy3TxziYnW0WktqMBCmF0JXHFuOXATZjpRxir9RwiMCWevMr0k4YZPrQYAo6_vt_xPGJFguL8H9FYXMqKM1SV0XxIZcjJYAodKWQ/s790/image-13.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiBoC9uWYHa80_quSEnAf6KSWUAeFNmUhJ-qfSQ1evZ1kHlYi-EcSxOnUb73ZM8b0zHZNXDMhKnoLfq1oGNF7tim0Sy3TxziYnW0WktqMBCmF0JXHFuOXATZjpRxir9RwiMCWevMr0k4YZPrQYAo6_vt_xPGJFguL8H9FYXMqKM1SV0XxIZcjJYAodKWQ/w320-h210/image-13.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>His big breakthrough came when he created a successful incandescent lightbulb. As I mentioned earlier, others had already been making light bulbs. British inventor Joseph Swan obtained the first patent for a light bulb in Britain two years before Edison patented the lightbulb.</p>



<p><a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/US205144A/en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://patents.google.com/patent/US205144A/en</a></p>



<p>Electric lamp Sawyer and Man Meanwhile, in America, William Sawyer and Albon Man received a U.S. patent for the incandescent lamp in 1878.</p>



<h2>What did Edison do?</h2>



<p>He improved the bulb. Previous ones had only been able to work for merely a few minutes at a time. By October 1879, Edison had an “aha” moment. His bulb with a carbonized filament burned continuously for 14.5 hours. But that still wasn’t good enough for him. He and his assistant tested thousands of plant materials and finally came up with a filament made from bamboo that could last up to 1,200 hours. In 1880, Edison received a historic patent for an improvement to electric lamps.</p>



<p>It’s been debated whether Edison’s patent infringed on Sawyer and Man’s previous patent. Eventually, Edison’s American lighting company merged with the Thomson-Houston Electric Company – which made incandescent bulbs under the Sawyer-Man patent. Together, they formed General Electric. On New Year’s Eve, 1879, Edison lit up New York’s Christie Street, marking the dawn of the electric age.</p>



<p>This was at a time when the world still relied on candlesticks. He then began to mass produce and sell them. But he didn’t stop with just improving the bulb. Edison then began working on building a system to carry electricity so people could use his light bulbs. In 1882, he set up a large generator plant on Pearl Street in lower Manhattan and lit the street with electricity. He became rich and famous. And…ruthless. Like when he tried to discredit a rival form of electricity.</p>



<p>Edison’s generating system uses direct current, which has its flaws. DC travels through a power line in one direction at a constant voltage but can only go up to a mile or so before losing power, so a generating plant was required every few blocks. He hired a young engineer to improve upon his DC generators. But Nikola Tesla came up with a better solution: alternating current. AC periodically changes direction and can also vary its voltage.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiCcG6Pe83JDJHL52IRn65z8iJwV3MKdu1tcShUekpgwB9rH9R3kkewCI65w2mi0SUOgSc6tLs7AcDrqk33s4Ug3gS-UGiVYgt5ZkG0GAXcP2ZHxDtpCCmfxWY0PJlO8OH1FG8Dh2mSeyQGojEwrCQBAXgrx2ybNrcovbJVzu3jUMhAtdCz2a54QLe7kw/s565/image-14.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiCcG6Pe83JDJHL52IRn65z8iJwV3MKdu1tcShUekpgwB9rH9R3kkewCI65w2mi0SUOgSc6tLs7AcDrqk33s4Ug3gS-UGiVYgt5ZkG0GAXcP2ZHxDtpCCmfxWY0PJlO8OH1FG8Dh2mSeyQGojEwrCQBAXgrx2ybNrcovbJVzu3jUMhAtdCz2a54QLe7kw/s320/image-14.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>It has a long-range and never runs out of power. Yet when Tesla tried to convince Edison of the advantages of AC, his boss wasn’t having any of it. Edison didn’t want to lose the royalties he earned from his DC patents. Tesla’s AC system caught the attention of American industrialist George Westinghouse who bought up Tesla’s patents.</p>



<p>AC generators were spreading fast across the country – faster than Edison’s DC system. So to discredit his rivals’ AC system, Edison devised an ugly strategy. He gave boys who lived around his New Jersey lab 25 cents for every stray dog they brought him and organized public electrocutions of these dogs with AC.</p>



<p>Edison took every opportunity to question the safety of Tesla’s AC system, declaring: “Westinghouse will murder a customer within six months after he installs a system of any size,” the adage goes. Edison publicly opposed the death penalty, but privately funded the first AC-powered electric chair. The state of New York had commissioned his former assistant Harold Brown to build the chair.</p>



<p>Brown pushed to have it powered by AC using a Westinghouse generator that he surreptitiously secured through another company. But his schemes didn’t work; AC would go on to power the world, much to Edison’s dismay.</p>



<p>Yet, Edison was more famous than Tesla and certainly a lot wealthier. Tesla died very poor – I’ve done a series of videos on what led to Tesla’s tragic demise which I’ll link to in my description. Edison patented a whopping 1,093 inventions in his lifetime! He managed thousands of skilled scientists, machinists, and designers who researched, developed, and manufactured new technologies.</p>



<h2>Where did Edison’s real genius lie?</h2>



<p>As Graham Moore writes in his novel The Last Days of Night about the feud between Edison and Westinghouse and Tesla: “His genius was not in inventing; rather, it was in inventing a system of the invention. Dozens of researchers and engineers and developmental tinkerers labored beneath Edison in a carefully constructed hierarchical organization that he founded and oversaw.”</p>



<p>In order words, Thomas Edison was not a genius inventor or a thief but a savvy businessman who had a knack for managing people. It was his shrewdness as a manager that allowed him to turn laboratory discoveries into technological marvels in the marketplace even if many of the original ideas came from someone else. Regardless of how you feel about Thomas Edison, his contributions have undoubtedly improved our lives.</p>



<p>To conclude, Whether you’re a fan of him or Nikola Tesla – what they both had in common was a firm grasp of math and science.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cluefill.com/thomas-alva-edisons-astonishing-story/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
