<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tesla &#8211; Cluefill</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cluefill.com/tag/tesla/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cluefill.com</link>
	<description>World of Randomness...</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 18:18:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cluefill.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Cluefill-Favicon.png</url>
	<title>Tesla &#8211; Cluefill</title>
	<link>https://cluefill.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Top 10 Greatest Facts about Nikola Tesla &#038; his untold Story&#8230;</title>
		<link>https://cluefill.com/top-10-greatest-facts-about-nikola-tesla-his-untold-story/</link>
					<comments>https://cluefill.com/top-10-greatest-facts-about-nikola-tesla-his-untold-story/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dinesh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 17:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here are some interesting facts about Nikola Tesla that many people may not know. Nikola Tesla’s Ideas weren’t recognized by ... <a title="Top 10 Greatest Facts about Nikola Tesla &#038; his untold Story&#8230;" class="read-more" href="https://cluefill.com/top-10-greatest-facts-about-nikola-tesla-his-untold-story/" aria-label="More on Top 10 Greatest Facts about Nikola Tesla &#038; his untold Story&#8230;">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>Here are some interesting facts about Nikola Tesla that many people may not know.</h2>



<ul>
<li>Nikola Tesla was a polyglot and spoke eight languages fluently, including English, German, French, Italian, Hungarian, Czech, Serbo-Croatian, and Latin.</li>



<li>He was a vegetarian and had a fear of germs, which caused him to avoid eating meat.</li>



<li>Tesla was an early advocate of wireless communication, and his experiments led to the development of radio.</li>



<li>He was a cat lover and had several cats throughout his life.</li>



<li>He was a strong believer in the power of the mind and often gave lectures on the power of positive thinking.</li>



<li>He was a prolific inventor, with over 300 patents to his name.</li>



<li>He was a fan of pigeons and often fed them in the park near his apartment.</li>



<li>He was a fan of literature, particularly Shakespeare, and was often seen reading at his laboratory.</li>



<li>He was a strong believer in the power of the imagination and often said, “The vision that you glorify in your mind, the ideal that you enthrone in your heart – this you will build your life by, and this you will become.”</li>



<li>He was a fan of music and was known to play the violin. He also invented the Tesla Coil, which is used to create musical notes.</li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjiP8PxB7OfHtXAKu7HtQhBjullGHtyiusbNUldT-SiBU6EFCuHjMV3JcyhIYaCCjH-37A-xt6LQMUbajbM68a1xHY4rSVn_YzQLbI80jE11cML8RZWd0RxuG7JLfkjuorwUHOlAmuaAULeOAEsL-hq2AdH_SroGJb20v5WygzJuXaspPmsdIgRQuAlYA/s990/image-5.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjiP8PxB7OfHtXAKu7HtQhBjullGHtyiusbNUldT-SiBU6EFCuHjMV3JcyhIYaCCjH-37A-xt6LQMUbajbM68a1xHY4rSVn_YzQLbI80jE11cML8RZWd0RxuG7JLfkjuorwUHOlAmuaAULeOAEsL-hq2AdH_SroGJb20v5WygzJuXaspPmsdIgRQuAlYA/w320-h143/image-5.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<h2>Nikola Tesla’s Ideas weren’t recognized by everyone</h2>



<p>Despite his many accomplishments, Nikola Tesla was not considered as a better scientist by many people due to his unorthodox methods and eccentric personality. He was considered to be a visionary and was ahead of his time in many regards, but his unconventional approach to science and technology did not sit well with many people. Additionally, his ambitious ideas and projects often failed to materialize due to lack of funding and resources. These factors contributed to his lack of recognition in his lifetime, despite his many accomplishments.</p>



<h2>Futuristic Ideas of Nikola Tesla</h2>



<p>Nikola Tesla had a wide range of ideas and theories outside of his inventions. Many of his theories focused on the power of energy, frequency and vibration, and he believed that all matter was composed of these elements. He also developed the concept of scalar waves, which he believed could be used to transmit energy, information and even time travel.</p>



<p>He was also a proponent of free energy and believed that a form of energy could be harnessed from the Earth’s atmosphere. He developed theories on the use of wireless power transmission, as well as robotics and artificial intelligence. Additionally, he had ideas on the use of electricity as a form of medicine and healing, as well as the concept of a “world brain” that could be used to share knowledge and ideas.</p>



<h2>Time Travel Idea of Nikola Tesla</h2>



<p>Nikola Tesla did not focus more on time travel for a few reasons. Firstly, he was far ahead of his time and his theories were often considered too outlandish to be taken seriously. Additionally, time travel was not a topic that was widely discussed or accepted in the late 19th and early 20th centuries, and Tesla likely felt that more research and experimentation was needed before it could be taken seriously. Finally, Tesla was a prolific inventor, and he likely felt that his time was better spent on more practical inventions, such as wireless power transmission and robotics.</p>



<p>Nikola Tesla’s wireless power transmission is possible in real life. Wireless power transmission is a technology that uses electromagnetic fields to transfer energy from a source to a receiver without the need for any physical connection. This technology has been used in a variety of applications, including powering medical implants, charging electric vehicles, and providing lighting. Tesla’s own experiments with wireless power transmission have been replicated, and wireless power transmission is now a reality.</p>



<p>Nikola Tesla was a highly respected scientist and inventor, and his work was admired by many. However, his ideas and theories were often controversial and not always accepted by the scientific community. Tesla had a number of well-known supporters, including Thomas <a class="wpil_keyword_link" href="https://cluefill.com/2023/02/22/thomas-alva-edisons-astonishing-story/" title="Edison" data-wpil-keyword-link="linked">Edison</a> and Mark Twain, but also encountered criticism and resistance from some quarters.</p>



<p>Some of his incomplete inventions or ideas include long-range wireless energy transfer, electric powered supersonic airships, humanoid robots, and controlling flows or fluid current. Tesla’s work in these areas was ahead of its time and has only recently been appreciated by scientists. For example, his invention to control flows or fluid currents is now being used in ways that were not previously realized.</p>



<p>Elon Musk is a fan of Nikola Tesla. He has said that Tesla is an inspiration to him, and has donated a million dollars to the Tesla Science Centre in honor of the inventor. He has also named his electric car company Tesla Motors in tribute to Tesla’s work.</p>



<h2>Nikola Tesla’s End</h2>



<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nikola_Tesla" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nikola Tesla</a>&nbsp;died on Jan 7, 1943, alone and in debt, on the 33rd floor of the Hotel New Yorker. He was 86 and had been in declining health for the last 10 years of his life. He was found in his bed by a maid, having passed away from a coronary thrombosis.</p>



<h2>How are Nikola Tesla’s greatest inventions used by everyone today?</h2>



<p>When you use any device that is powered by electricity, you have a&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nikola_Tesla" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Nikola Tesla</a>&nbsp;is one of the greatest scientists to ever live. However, even though the genius had a weird personal life, he left some pretty terrifying predictions that the authorities tried to keep secret but have just been made public.</p>



<p>Most times the lives of brilliant figures are interesting, but Nikola Tesla’s life was much more than interesting even as he left behind a legacy that will last forever. Nikola Tesla was born in 1856 as an Austro-Hungarian Empire subject in the mountainous region of Lika on the Balkan Peninsula.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjDPqsNj98u25vsh25U8IdtkWVabprUsfEe4740xjuYmj6qTlcAc2Y7Fpy0gU2u9fRHBNfHLjELs6nokY5xoqVCLl3vLNDnph0CFXTGv2FF3U_Xo5zZeH5mUiDRIpkBt2pzOFodQM9UcknapNEeR3FV_hVpw3SyUQpdZc3ufHGi3qHAnV9QmUsaNFMF-g/s1036/image-2.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjDPqsNj98u25vsh25U8IdtkWVabprUsfEe4740xjuYmj6qTlcAc2Y7Fpy0gU2u9fRHBNfHLjELs6nokY5xoqVCLl3vLNDnph0CFXTGv2FF3U_Xo5zZeH5mUiDRIpkBt2pzOFodQM9UcknapNEeR3FV_hVpw3SyUQpdZc3ufHGi3qHAnV9QmUsaNFMF-g/w320-h179/image-2.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>His father, Malutin, and mother, Duca, were both of Serbian descent. Tesla’s father was a stern but loving Orthodox priest who also happened to be a gifted writer and poet. Tesla immersed himself in his father’s library from a young age, and Tesla obviously got some of his creative traits from his mother, who was a hard-working woman with many talents. She designed appliances to help with household and farm chores, including a mechanical egg beater.</p>



<p>Tesla began his education at home and later attended a gymnasium in Carlstadt, Croatia, where he excelled in his studies. During this time, young Nico came across a steel engraving of Niagara Falls in his mind. A massive water wheel was being turned by the more powerful current. He solemnly told an uncle that one day he would travel to America and capture energy in this manner, and he did exactly that 30 years later.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiPmpE_6wlnSAk5UXrKMS5VYotz1re4yzI51PAtx8IZxSEHS3ED5ItUU_fOCsF63Qk9Lt71jBuB3ZJJSse74szXS7pz4tH99U2DFfB393PJj7GYo0xzBMdd_ayrXbJiypzQCYxHdgEI-JIXI8G_yxkl1sWYnxvocRfLhPEeNToE-wXaejgWVYED8Zu4BA/s1534/image-1.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiPmpE_6wlnSAk5UXrKMS5VYotz1re4yzI51PAtx8IZxSEHS3ED5ItUU_fOCsF63Qk9Lt71jBuB3ZJJSse74szXS7pz4tH99U2DFfB393PJj7GYo0xzBMdd_ayrXbJiypzQCYxHdgEI-JIXI8G_yxkl1sWYnxvocRfLhPEeNToE-wXaejgWVYED8Zu4BA/s320/image-1.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>Tesla began his mechanical and electrical engineering studies at the Polytechnic School, where it didn’t take long for his brilliance to shine through. One day, a physics teacher showed Tesla’s class a new Graham Dynamo, which could be used as both a motor and a generator by using direct current. After observing it for a while, Tesla speculated that it might be possible to eliminate commutators, which are inefficient sparking connections.</p>



<p>His professor joked that this would be like constructing a perpetual motion machine, but Tesla would not let go of the idea, which he pondered for years, and he intuitively knew that the solution lay in alternating electric currents. It wasn’t until Tesla was 24 and working for the central telephone exchange in Budapest that the answer came to him.</p>



<p>He said one afternoon he was walking through the city park with a friend and reciting poetry when a portion of the poem he uttered jolted an idea in his might. He quickly grabbed a stick and drew the diagram on the set, and the wild has not been the same since.</p>



<h2>Company that hired Tesla</h2>



<p>Tesla was hired by electric power companies in Strasbourg and Paris to improve their DC generation facilities after his discovery in Budapest. He tried unsuccessfully to interest investors in his AC motor concept in Germany and France, but it was obvious that in order to realize his vision he would need to meet another of the world’s greatest electrical engineers.</p>



<p>Thomas Alva Edison Tesla arrived in New York City at the age of 28 and was astounded by what he found; he stated that he left behind a very beautiful artistic and fascinating homeland to live in a place that was machined rough and unappealing the genius felt America was a century behind Europe in terms of civilization.</p>



<p>While Tesla, the Serbian immigrant, hoped to start a new life with four cents in his pockets, some mathematical computations, a drawing of the Flying Machine concept, Tesla’s life would intertwine with Edison’s in the late 1870s, when electricity was first introduced to New York.</p>



<h2>Edison and Tesla</h2>



<p>Edison’s incandescent lamp sparked unprecedented demand for electricity, and his direct current power plant on Pearl Street in lower Manhattan quickly became a monopoly. Single poles carried dozens of crooked crossbeams supporting sagging wires on the streets, and exposed electrical wiring was a constant danger. Unwary children would scale the poles only to meet an untimely electrical death. I know two grey men, and you are one of them; this young man is the other. Tesla then went on to describe his engineering work and plans for an alternating current motor, despite Edison’s lack of knowledge and desire to learn more.</p>



<p>Edison perceived AC power as a threat, but there was something different about Tesla, and Edison hired him right away to improve his DC generation plans. Tesla claimed Edison promised him fifty thousand dollars if he succeeded, possibly thinking it was an impossible task, but the prospect of so much money was great motivation for the poor immigrant. Tesla and Edison shared a genius trait in that neither of them seemed to require much sleep. Edison could go on for days catnapping on a sofa in his office.</p>



<p>Tesla claimed that he worked from 10 p.m. to 5 a.m. the next day to build the Edison Machine. Tesla claimed that even in his old age he only slept two or three hours per night. The resemblance ended there, though Tesla relied on flashes of inspiration, visualizing the invention in his mind before proceeding to the construction stage. Edison was a trial and error man who defined invention as “five percent inspiration and 95 percent perspiration.” Edison was a self-taught artist.</p>



<p>After Tesla received his formal education in Europe, it was only a matter of time before the differences became a source of contention. Tesla announced the completion of his work several months after Edison hired him.</p>



<p>When Tesla asked to be paid, Edison was taken aback. He explained that the fifty thousand dollar offer was made in jest. Tesla resigned immediately, shocked and disgusted to be fired, and went bankrupt. Tesla turned to menial jobs. The word soon spread that a foreigner with unusual talent was digging ditches to survive. Investors approached Tesla and requested that he develop a better method for arc lighting.</p>



<h2>Financial agreement</h2>



<p>Despite the fact that this was not the opportunity he had hoped for, the group agreed to finance the Tesla electric light company. Tesla got to work and created a one-of-a-kind r-clamp with a beautiful design and efficiency. Unfortunately, Tesla was out of his depth in the financial aspects; all of the profits went to the investors, leaving Tesla with a pile of worthless stock certificates, but his fortunes were about to change. Mr. A.K. Brown of Western Union agreed to invest in Tesla’s AC motor concept.</p>



<p>Tesla quickly developed all of the components of the system of alternating current power generation and transmission that is used universally throughout the world today in a small laboratory just a short distance from Edison’s office during this time, saying, “The motors I built there were exactly as I imagined them. I made no attempt to improve the design instead simply reproducing the images as they appeared to my eyes.”</p>



<p>Tesla applied for seven U.S. patents in the field of polyphase AC motors and power transmission in November and December of 1887 for a complete system of generators, transformers, and transmission lines. Motors and lighting were included.</p>



<h2>How could a man look into the future needs?</h2>



<p>Here are some of the genius’s predictions. Number one, when Wireless is perfectly applied, the entire earth will be converted into a huge brain, in which all things, being particles of a real and rhythmic hope, will be able to communicate with one another instantly regardless of distance; not only that, but through television and telephony.</p>



<p>We will see and hear one another as perfectly as if we were face to face despite intervening distances of thousands of miles; and the instruments through which we shall see and hear one another as perfectly as All forms of static interference will be eliminated so that innumerable transmitters and receivers may be operated without interference.</p>



<p>It is more than probable that the household’s daily newspaper will be printed wirelessly in the home during the night, and domestic management problems of heat, light, and household mechanics will be freed from all labour through beneficent wireless power.</p>



<p>This is the Wi-Fi you connect to every day, starting as early as 1898. I propose to representatives of a large manufacturing concern the construction and public exhibition of an automobile. Carriage, if left to its own devices, would perform a wide range of operations involving something resembling judgment. This is the self-driving car; interestingly, a company named after him is one of the leaders in autonomous driving with autopilot number four.</p>



<p>When wireless power transmission becomes commercial, transport and transmission will be revolutionized. Already, motion pictures have been transmitted wirelessly over a short distance; later, the distance will be limitable, and by later, I mean only a few years hence. Perhaps the most valuable application of wireless energy will be the propulsion of flying machines that will carry no fuel and be free from any limitations of the present airplanes.</p>



<h3>The Wireless Ideas</h3>



<p>We shall ride from New York to Europe in a few hours. International boundaries will be largely obliterated, and a great step will be made towards the unification and harmonious existence of the various races inhabiting The Globe Wireless will not only make possible the supply of energy to regions that are otherwise inaccessible, but it will also be effective politically by harmonizing international interests and creating understanding instead of differences. These would be planes that do not need refueling.</p>



<p>The concept is based on the ability to transmit energy over long distances without using wires. number six I expect to photograph thoughts in 1893, while engaged in certain investigations, I became convinced that a definite image formed in thought must, by reflex action, produce a corresponding image on the retina which could be read by a suitable apparatus.</p>



<p>Now, if it is true that a thought reflects an image on the retina, it is a simple matter of illuminating the same property and taking photographs, and then using the ordinary methods which are available to project the image on a suitable apparatus.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhyCYq84NCdkOp4ioi7aH9MRraRWflcNVRnxwjOg7WZqCKVYTWb4ugq2wKBA0Hc-9ZKBnrLqr6naA99HDYT2S8_-HFCjPWWLUp3DoNcykmqvleyxq7a7YRaoofZfTnA00rWjLkjk-AMSiS0akWh0n8ty3jvNP5QivSaEyyLxGt97DxLyuIJu5HJihEU8Q/s799/image-3.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhyCYq84NCdkOp4ioi7aH9MRraRWflcNVRnxwjOg7WZqCKVYTWb4ugq2wKBA0Hc-9ZKBnrLqr6naA99HDYT2S8_-HFCjPWWLUp3DoNcykmqvleyxq7a7YRaoofZfTnA00rWjLkjk-AMSiS0akWh0n8ty3jvNP5QivSaEyyLxGt97DxLyuIJu5HJihEU8Q/s320/image-3.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>I believe that the development of the Flying Machine will outpace that of the automobile, and I anticipate that Mr. Ford will make significant contributions to this progress. The problem of parking automobiles and providing separate roads for commercial and pleasure traffic will be solved, belted parking towers will spring up in our major cities, and roads will be multiplied out of sheer necessity until they are rendered obsolete when civilization exchanges wheels for winks.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiQgujdLX0q7xfZMQdX6RItS7sHZ7yWXfQwRdPCm8kWBCK_hQePb48m8qmVWrQ0cKFhmR1F6IfiFMIQ4BvXR1gA-T-sXFEh-uLPmH9Zh3VOlF4XQ_qjJPTTj0LRvafe3Bnmd4RPMJO4jd47wsIS67Qs_NO1ev_Wi2bCGJG9KeGcuONqJgsw40bY1WAqgQ/s757/image-4.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiQgujdLX0q7xfZMQdX6RItS7sHZ7yWXfQwRdPCm8kWBCK_hQePb48m8qmVWrQ0cKFhmR1F6IfiFMIQ4BvXR1gA-T-sXFEh-uLPmH9Zh3VOlF4XQ_qjJPTTj0LRvafe3Bnmd4RPMJO4jd47wsIS67Qs_NO1ev_Wi2bCGJG9KeGcuONqJgsw40bY1WAqgQ/s320/image-4.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>The FBI finally declassified some 250 pages of Tesla-related documents under the Freedom of Information Act in 2016 after years of Fielding questions about possible cover-ups, the bureau followed up with two more releases, the most recent in March 2018. Despite the release of these documents, many questions remain unanswered, and some of Tesla’s files remain unaccounted for three weeks after his death.</p>



<p>According to the declassified documents, an electrical engineer from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) was tasked with reviewing his papers to see if they contained any ideas of significant value. Dr. John G. Trump stated that his analysis revealed Tesla’s efforts to be primarily speculative, philosophical, and promotional in nature, and that the papers did not include new, sound, workable principles or methods for realizing such results. The scientist’s name is undoubtedly familiar because John G. Trump was the uncle of Donald J. Trump, the 45th President of the United States.</p>



<p>He was the younger brother of Trump’s father Fred and helped design x-ray machines that helped cancer patients as well as work on radar research for the allies during World War II. Then there’s the perplexing issue of the missing files. Tesla’s files and other materials were sent to Belgrade, Serbia, in 1952 after a U.S. court declared Kuzmanovic the rightful heir to his uncle’s estate, where they now reside in the Nicola Tesla Museum.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>To conclude, Nikola Tesla was a genius inventor and scientist who made incredible contributions to science and technology. His inventions and theories laid the foundation for many modern technologies, and his ideas continue to inspire innovation today. His work in the field of electricity revolutionized the world and he is widely respected for his ground breaking ideas and inventions. Tesla’s ideas and inventions are considered ahead of their time, and many believe that technology is still missing his genius.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cluefill.com/top-10-greatest-facts-about-nikola-tesla-his-untold-story/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tesla&#8217;s 5 hilarious struggles and fates : Difference between Thomas Alva Edison and Nikola Tesla</title>
		<link>https://cluefill.com/teslas-5-hilarious-struggles-and-fates-difference-between-thomas-alva-edison-and-nikola-tesla/</link>
					<comments>https://cluefill.com/teslas-5-hilarious-struggles-and-fates-difference-between-thomas-alva-edison-and-nikola-tesla/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dinesh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 06:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Facts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tesla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Golden Century The nineteenth century was a time of great inventors and inventions. Along the way, Thomas Edison became ... <a title="Tesla&#8217;s 5 hilarious struggles and fates : Difference between Thomas Alva Edison and Nikola Tesla" class="read-more" href="https://cluefill.com/teslas-5-hilarious-struggles-and-fates-difference-between-thomas-alva-edison-and-nikola-tesla/" aria-label="More on Tesla&#8217;s 5 hilarious struggles and fates : Difference between Thomas Alva Edison and Nikola Tesla">Read more</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>The Golden Century</h2>



<p>The nineteenth century was a time of great inventors and inventions. Along the way, Thomas Edison became one of the best-known and most admired inventors in history. Nikola Tesla is arguably less well-known. Only recently has he attracted renewed attention, thanks in part to the electric car company that bears his name. In 1884, when Tesla was 28 years old, he sailed for New York with only four cents in his pocket.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEisJGEkkA4jUXduhlU3yCljRLAP6owa_nIbRl76ppB4XM36tvC_sZ-ivuPO_7NZuRttVmoAUsmiPLs9hOSI9GdOrOG8e8BZKdClqjwlFQ2TXye_sVTzB05mY2hhNz2pj1ib_BHbmacRV2IRrJFKf10n_QrrbCauNMxKidEWSIJ8tIPK7LNAFwWuiGvBXA/s679/image-19.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEisJGEkkA4jUXduhlU3yCljRLAP6owa_nIbRl76ppB4XM36tvC_sZ-ivuPO_7NZuRttVmoAUsmiPLs9hOSI9GdOrOG8e8BZKdClqjwlFQ2TXye_sVTzB05mY2hhNz2pj1ib_BHbmacRV2IRrJFKf10n_QrrbCauNMxKidEWSIJ8tIPK7LNAFwWuiGvBXA/w320-h186/image-19.png" alt="Tesla Discussing" title="Discussion with colleagues"/></a></figure>



<p>His money and some of his luggage were stolen on the way over. Like other immigrants, Tesla came to America for work. He had been hired as an engineer at <a class="wpil_keyword_link" href="https://cluefill.com/2023/02/22/thomas-alva-edisons-astonishing-story/" title="Edison" data-wpil-keyword-link="linked">Edison</a> Machine Works in Manhattan. Tesla admired Edison, recalling: “One of the great events in my life was my first meeting with Edison.” “This wonderful man, who had received no scientific training yet had accomplished so much, filled me with amazement.”</p>



<h2>How Edision was impressed</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjJvJQykvEJqBu9Q_NOk7yzX7eH4ddYNNTMwOZ29iEeq4-fgx7rYXxW81djPb1f52h7K_gs1wl-ZUuvzFWn4Cm4ud3RlFXGs4gbR9br6kkZiegJskAQbyCH0npEiboUfufVIQyEeht1oihouR1L-SUnuHECEgnnTsqOfCdlQqAB03HMPX_H4WhXPtc5qg/s472/image-16.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjJvJQykvEJqBu9Q_NOk7yzX7eH4ddYNNTMwOZ29iEeq4-fgx7rYXxW81djPb1f52h7K_gs1wl-ZUuvzFWn4Cm4ud3RlFXGs4gbR9br6kkZiegJskAQbyCH0npEiboUfufVIQyEeht1oihouR1L-SUnuHECEgnnTsqOfCdlQqAB03HMPX_H4WhXPtc5qg/w244-h320/image-16.png" alt="Tesla" title="Nikola Tesla"/></a></figure>



<p>Edison was also impressed with the young engineer, remarking to an assistant: “…this is a damn good man!” It didn’t take long, however, for things to turn sour as the two men disagreed over how electricity should be delivered to the masses. In 1879, Edison created the first practical incandescent lightbulb and then built a system to carry electricity so people could use his new invention.</p>



<p>He opened up his first power plant in New York in 1882, supported by his direct current electrical system known as DC. A network of underground cables would carry electricity from a generator to homes and businesses. But his DC generators kept failing. So he hired a young Serbian engineer to improve them. Tesla saw the weaknesses of direct current, which travels through a power line in one direction at a constant voltage.</p>



<p>But there’s a critical flaw: it can only go up to a mile before losing power. Tesla felt he had come up with a better solution: alternating current. AC periodically changes direction and can also vary its voltage. The crucial advantage is that it can travel hundreds of miles without losing power. Yet when Tesla tried to convince Edison of the advantages of AC, his boss wasn’t having any of it. Edison didn’t want to lose the royalties he earned from his DC patents.</p>



<h2>Claims made</h2>



<p>Tesla claimed Edison promised him $50,000 if he could improve his DC generators, and when he did, Edison refused to pay up and is said to have responded, “Tesla, you don’t understand our American humour.” So Tesla quit after just a few months on the job, writing in his diary, “Goodbye to the Edison Machine Works.” Tesla set out on his own, hoping to find investors interested in his concept for an AC motor that he had patented. Yet he struggled.</p>



<p>Alternating current was a new technology. not something anyone had ever seen before. He even briefly had to resort to digging ditches just to survive. But there was one person who took a chance on him. Entrepreneur George Westinghouse saw the potential of AC. He believed AC was the missing link in long-distance power transmission.</p>



<p>So he purchased Tesla’s AC patents for $60,000 and offered Tesla stock and royalties of $2.50 for each horsepower of electricity sold. All of this is worth millions today. Edison tried to do everything he could to discredit Tesla’s AC system so that DC would be the preferred choice to power homes. He found an ally in J.P. Morgan, at the time the most powerful banker in America. This would lead to the birth of General Electric.</p>



<h2>The War of Currents</h2>



<p>The battle against&nbsp;<a href="https://cluefill.com/2023/02/22/top-10-greatest-facts-about-nikola-tesla-his-untold-story/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tesla</a>&nbsp;and Westinghouse is now known as the War of the Currents. And in many ways, it was a propaganda war launched by Edison to try to convince the public that AC was dangerous. He zeroed in on the fact that alternating current operates at much higher voltages than direct current. When the state of New York commissioned an electricity salesman named Harold Brown to build the electric chair, Edison paid him behind the scenes to use his rival’s AC generators secured through a second-hand dealer.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi5jziSDIXRF11j2oxZ2tPPKLqOtf7LuEwG0flSJfCs6YAKReqZa_g9moD4Df3JKzIti0IkiNkyUJHGw3ryZ-9jpNFqjxJKYXCTzmTOuCqCEKqOw6w05JRCqHv3GRoAFveNbH7u7v_kf0VZYSAhjzQL_PPCY4KleyTwqDg1kxJMm7LNicRSgW1ISjF3Wg/s837/image-15.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi5jziSDIXRF11j2oxZ2tPPKLqOtf7LuEwG0flSJfCs6YAKReqZa_g9moD4Df3JKzIti0IkiNkyUJHGw3ryZ-9jpNFqjxJKYXCTzmTOuCqCEKqOw6w05JRCqHv3GRoAFveNbH7u7v_kf0VZYSAhjzQL_PPCY4KleyTwqDg1kxJMm7LNicRSgW1ISjF3Wg/w320-h216/image-15.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>Brown also used AC to electrocute dogs at&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G6xGuv6I5NI" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Edison’s</a>&nbsp;laboratory in New Jersey, which Edison recalled in articles he published, writing: “I have myself seen a large, healthy dog killed instantly by the alternating current.” Other animals were not immune to his schemes. Edison’s company electrocuted a circus elephant named Topsy using AC and produced a film about it. His anti-AC crusade may or may not have also come from a genuine safety concern.</p>



<p>He wrote a letter warning the president of his electric light company of the danger of AC, declaring: “Just as certain as death, Westinghouse will kill a customer within six months after he puts in a system of any size.” Sure enough, there were several accidental deaths due to the high voltages of AC in the late 1880s in New York and several other cities. In one incident, telegraph lineman John Feeks’ body was left hanging from tangled wires in front of a horrified crowd. His death led to laws to move AC lines underground in New York City.</p>



<h2>Dramatic display of current</h2>



<p>Tesla felt that the only way to show that AC was safe was to demonstrate it to himself. In a dramatic display at Columbia University, he grasped a brass ball in each hand and touched the terminals of a high-voltage, high-frequency transformer now known as a Tesla coil. 250,000 volts raced across the surface of his body.</p>



<p>A newspaper reported that he was surrounded by “tongues of electric flame.” In 1893, Tesla and Westinghouse scored a big win when they beat out Edison to light up the Chicago World’s Fair using alternating current. The first all-electric fair in history Three years later, Tesla lit up the city of Buffalo using AC motors powered by the waters of Niagara Falls. This was Tesla’s childhood dream.</p>



<p>As a kid, he saw an image of the Falls and told his uncle that one day he’d go to America and capture the energy of Niagara. The first hydroelectric power plant at Niagara Falls would mark the beginning of the electrification of the world. When he gave a speech at the opening ceremony, Tesla said, “It is a monument worthy of our scientific age.” “It signifies the subjugation of natural forces to the service of man, the discontinuance of barbarous methods, and the relief of millions from want and suffering.”</p>



<h2>Today’s scenario</h2>



<p>Today, almost every home in the world is powered by AC, whereas DC powers smaller items or anything that uses batteries, from your electric toothbrush to the clock on the wall. Despite the success of AC, Tesla never enjoyed the fame and fortune that Edison did. because Edison was not only an inventor. He was a businessman, honing his craft at the age of 13 when he started selling candy, newspapers, and vegetables on trains and turned an amazing profit of $50 a week in his day—about $1,600 today.</p>



<p>Edison would likely have made a different choice when confronted with the challenging situation that Tesla faced next. The war of the currents took a financial toll on Westinghouse, whose company racked up millions of dollars in debt. When Westinghouse begged Tesla to lower his royalty rate to save the company, Tesla did more than that. He tore up his contract, relinquishing his royalties altogether. It’s estimated that Tesla willingly walked away from $12 million in royalties in his day, which today would be worth well over $300 million.</p>



<p>Those royalties were so valuable that they would have accrued over time to turn Tesla into the world’s first billionaire. In return, Westinghouse paid him a lump sum of $216,000 for the right to use his AC patents forever, which is roughly $5 million today. Tesla’s decision would hurt him dearly because he ended up short on cash to fund his other grand ideas. He had discovered that his powerful coil made it possible to send and receive radio signals. But in 1895, a fire broke out at the building housing his New York lab as he was about to transmit a signal 50 miles to West Point, New York.</p>



<h2>The blaze destroyed everything</h2>



<p>His models, designs, notes, and tools. The timing was terrible because Italian inventor Guglielmo Marconi was also developing radio in England, sending Morse-code-based signals. Tesla still managed to beat Marconi to the punch by filing American patents for the radio first, in 1897. When Marconi tried to do the same a few years later, the U.S. Patent Office turned him down because his inventions were too similar to Tesla.</p>



<p>Repeated applications were rejected. But Marconi did attract the attention of none other than Edison, who invested in him and became a consulting engineer at Marconi’s company. The Italian’s greatest achievement came in 1901 when he received the first radio signal sent across the Atlantic from a transmitter in southwest England to St. John’s, Newfoundland, in eastern Canada. This won Marconi international fame. and he had to use Tesla’s patents to achieve it. But Tesla didn’t mind. When one of his engineers said, “Looks as if Marconi got the jump on you,” Tesla replied, “Marconi is a good fellow.” Let him continue. He is using seventeen of my patents.</p>



<h2>Unfortunately, no patent is truly safe.</h2>



<p>In 1904, the Patent Office decided inexplicably to rewrite history by awarding Marconi a patent for the invention of the radio, reversing its earlier decisions. It gave no reason. But it didn’t hurt that Marconi had the financial backing of Edison and other influential people. In 1909, Marconi won the Nobel Prize in physics for the invention of the radio. Tesla was furious. and sued the Marconi Company for infringement. The radio incident led Tesla to lose business opportunities.</p>



<p>For example, Tesla had a grand vision for wireless electricity. His proposal initially caught the attention of J.P. Morgan, who put up $150,000 to build a giant transmission tower in 1901. Tesla believed the 187-foot, 57-meter-tall Wardenclyffe Tower in Long Island, New York, was the start of a system that could deliver electricity without wires around the globe. Anyone with the right equipment could tap into it. He imagined a scenario where “…it will be possible for a businessman in New York to dictate instructions and have them instantly appear in type at his office in London or elsewhere.”</p>



<h2>Telecommunication infrastructure</h2>



<p>It was incredibly prescient to envision telecommunications infrastructure much like today’s Internet more than a century ago. But Tesla’s vision would never bear fruit. Electricity can indeed be transmitted through the air, but it’s impractical because of the amount of power needed to make it happen. So, Tesla appealed to Morgan for more money. It was all for nought. Morgan was throwing money in the other direction, towards Marconi.</p>



<p>Wardenclyffe Tower was never completed and would eventually be demolished, along with Tesla’s vision. Tesla was devastated and had a breakdown, lamenting, “It is not a dream.” “It’s a simple feat of scientific electrical engineering, but it’s expensive—blind, faint-hearted, sceptical world!”Tesla began to withdraw from that world. He showed signs of obsessive-compulsive disorder, which compelled him to do things in threes, including living in a hotel room that was divisible by the number three.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi2TwSVtRelY7xl3W7ILqC8MuT3I1Q9OaSYUBVMOQK_TAD8tt3AKnE4AMC69WiZodwNjCdCj-XjJEtm4ke5WOnhKn1SOIwWoqNI9jmdDBOD5utbIO8yIbLoPyBKsuMZ6DpAZfDI64yfRxn0J3Klj0Vil515anUsFKrF7yHzRQqWn-nf8fRpRCWOuvHHdg/s529/image-17.png" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi2TwSVtRelY7xl3W7ILqC8MuT3I1Q9OaSYUBVMOQK_TAD8tt3AKnE4AMC69WiZodwNjCdCj-XjJEtm4ke5WOnhKn1SOIwWoqNI9jmdDBOD5utbIO8yIbLoPyBKsuMZ6DpAZfDI64yfRxn0J3Klj0Vil515anUsFKrF7yHzRQqWn-nf8fRpRCWOuvHHdg/w320-h298/image-17.png" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>He spent the last decade of his life living out of a hotel paid for by the Westinghouse Corporation, which kept him on as a consultant. He was broke. And befriended pigeons. Edison, on the other hand, continued to reap immense rewards. Businesses and partnerships filled his life. By the time he died in 1931, he had patented a record 1,093 inventions.</p>



<p>There was the lightbulb, of course, but also the motion picture camera and the early record player called a phonograph. Today, he is considered one of the world’s greatest inventors. It was only after Tesla’s death that he got a modicum of justice for all that he had lost. When Tesla sued Marconi, the case dragged on in court for years.</p>



<h2>Macroni’s Passing</h2>



<p>Six months after Marconi’s passing in 1943, the U.S. Supreme Court ruled Marconi’s radio patents were invalid and awarded the patents for the radio to Tesla. But it had a selfish reason for doing so. Marconi’s company had sued the U.S. government for patent infringement during World War I. So to avoid the lawsuit altogether, the Supreme Court deemed Tesla the inventor of the radio.</p>



<p>Today, at the site where Tesla’s Wardenclyffe Tower once stood, is a science museum dedicated to the man whose dreams were not to be. The Tesla Science Center was made possible thanks to the financial support of thousands of Tesla fans, including Tesla CEO Elon Musk. Tesla’s prediction of data transmission without wires came true in the early 1990s.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cluefill.com/teslas-5-hilarious-struggles-and-fates-difference-between-thomas-alva-edison-and-nikola-tesla/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
